Adrien Lacquemant

alaq.io - github.com/alaq - linkedin.com/in/adrien-lacquemant/

adrien@alaq.io +1 (646) 410-3409

SUMMARY

Two years of experience as a Software Engineer delivering creative highly data-driven client-centric applications. I am excited to be part of a team and solve problems using my experience in spotting inefficiencies and creating automated solutions.

SKILLS

- Languages: JavaScript/TypeScript, C++, Common Lisp
- Proficient: React/Redux, Node.js, Unit testing with Mocha/Chai/Sinon, SQL

EXPERIENCE

Bloomberg L.P.

New York, NY

Senior Software Engineer May 2018 - Current o Overhaul of legacy trading applications, resulting in increased usability and uniformization of the trading experience.

- Design and build new features for the company's trading platforms and release them to our users.
- Spearhead the adoption of new technologies and improvement of development practices (type-checking, React, state-management).

Fullstack Academy of Code - major coding bootcamp

New York, NY

Teaching Fellow

Dec 2017 - Apr 2018

- Led code reviews and acted as a project manager for 4 teams of junior software engineers.
- Code paired, debugged/mentored technical concepts and best practices to 50 students on a daily basis.
- Led technical interviews in Javascript for prospective students 2 to 3 times a week.

Ara Global Group - medium sized electronics wholesaler

New York, NY

Software Engineer

May 2016 - Apr 2018

- Spearheaded re-engineering project to improve/automate asset processing and cataloging, reducing processing time by 25%.
- o Developed an in-house SaaS for systematic asset and sales monitoring per device leading to 20% in increased revenue.
- Wrote a data validation tool in JavaScript that ensured the accuracy of inventory and sales data feeds.

BISAM, Inc. - financial software vendor

New York, NY

Product Support Analyst

Jan 2015 - Apr 2016

- Troubleshot financial calculation issues raised by clients and Professional Services team.
- Supported defect resolution by identifying and replicating bugs.
- o Testing patch releases and managing deliveries.

Tortus Capital Management - value oriented hedge fund

New York, NY

Research Analyst

Jul 2013 - Jul 2014

- Completed financial analysis for over 30 distressed companies and recommended long/short positions.
- Traded and monitored the firm's securities on a daily basis.

Freelance Web Developer

Paris & New York, NY

Self Employed

2007 - 2017

- o Built from scratch over 30 websites for small and medium sized companies, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Recent examples include: icyclegreen.com, araglobalgroup.com, adht.parsons.edu/GeraldineStutz

PROJECTS

Propel ML - open source contributor

https://github.com/propelml/propel

GPU-backed numpy-like infrastructure for scientific computing in JavaScript.

Feb 2018 to April 2018

- Contributing to the front-end of a large Preact/Typescript open source project, using TDD.
- o Implementing of user profiles, and several other front-end features.

Device Extract, LLC. - founder & developer

An Electron app for cataloging mobile devices programmatically

June 2017 - April 2018

- Built with Electron, to access Android and iOS devices through the computer's serial ports.
- Scanned over 100,000 mobile devices successfully; extracting characteristics and basic diagnostics.

EDUCATION

Fullstack Academy of Code

New York, NY

Software Engineering Immersive Program

2017 Singapore

ESSEC Business School M.S. Financial Engineering

2013

Universite Paris Dauphine

Paris, France 2011

M.S. Finance & B.S. Management

+1 (646) 410-3409

Adrien Lacquemant

adrien@alaq.io